Victor Klynets

Full-stack JS Developer

Kyiv | +380509721609 | vityok3458@gmail.com in ua.linkedin.com/in/victor-klynets

About me

I am a **Full-stack JS Developer** with a decent experience in *architecting and building web applications* and finding new, more flexible, highly efficient, more synthetic as well as more performing and elegant ways to do it.

A far-sighted *problem preventer*. Being highly *adaptable*, I'm able to quickly pick up and *work with any architecture or libraries* required. I can estimate the time needed to complete a task (and a project), plan and lead the work of a team of 5-7 people to complete a project respecting the deadlines.

Passionate about creating a favorable work environment through effective coordination and communication with managers, designers, developers and clients to produce stand-out work. Good analytical thinking with talent for identifying, scrutinizing and improving work processes

Employment

Full-stack JS Developer

January 2017 - Present

Coingaming

- Building an interconnected architecture of applications
- Configuring CircleCI and GitlabCI
- Managing and deploying with Kubernetes
- Creating a microservice architecture using NodeJS combined with GraphQL
- Creating isomorphic applications using *Meteor*
- Developing Progressive Web Applications with React and Relay
- Creating bot applications using NodeJS
- Mentoring and tutoring new team members

Front-end developer

February 2016 - October 2016

Mixera

As a Lead Front-end Developer my responsibilities were:

- Making Single Page Applications with ExtJS and React/Redux
- Creating custom solutions and working with a large project
- Analyzing performance and developing better solutions
- Working in a team and managing tasks

Freelance Web Developer

November 2015 - January 2016

Independant Freelancer

- Developed websites for different clients
- Identified issues with existing web-sites and introduced smart and efficient fixes
- Conducted correspondence with clients to obtain more information and discussed design options as well as suggested relevant and unique product solutions
- Determined appropriate architecture to achieve the best troubleshooting options

Projects

Student course "Introduction to Frontend Development"

September 2016 - November 2016

Co-founder and speaker of the course

Education

Bachelor's Degree NTUU Kyiv Polytechnic Institute Studying software engineering. 2014 - Present

Soft Skills

- English(upper-intermediate),
 Hungarian(native speaker),
 Ukrainian(native speaker), Russian(native speaker)
- Problem solver with a can do attitude
- Good understanding of industrial and organization psychology principles
- High level of communication
- Highly self- motivated and directed
- Good analytical thinking with talent for identifying, scrutinizing and improving work processes
- Equally comfortable working as a member of a team and independently

Hard Skills

Performance optimization

Web page first loading time and Speed Index

Frontend Development

Building Single Page Applications and Progressive Web Applications with Server Side Rendering.

Backend Development

Architect, implement and maintain scalable backend software. (*Redis, RabbitMQ, Docker*)

JavaScript

Great knowledge of JavaScript (ES5-ES8).

JavaScript Frameworks and Libraries

Meteor, Sequelize, Mongoose, Express, React, Relay, Redux, Vue.js, jQuery, D3.js, ExtJS, Jest, Jasmine, Angular,

moment, i18next, socket.io, cron, lodash, winston and lots of other

Databases

- PostgreSQL
- MongoDB
- MySQL

Build systems and module bundlers

Webpack, Gulp, Grunt, Bower